Finding Aid to the Margaret Sanger papers SSC.MS.00138
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES XI. MICROFILM
  - SUBSERIES I: CORRESPONDENCE
    - 1960
      - February-June [continues onto reel S56 through to reel S57] (Box 62, Folder 1-6)
      - July-November (Box 63, Folder 1-7)
      - December [start of reel S58] (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - 1961
      - January-May (Box 64, Folder 2-6)
      - June-December [continues onto reel S58 through to reel S59] (Box 65, Folder 1-5)
    - 1962
      - January-March (Box 65, Folder 6-8)
      - April-December (Box 66, Folder 1)
      - 1963-1966 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Undated correspondence to Margaret Sanger
      - Unknown author / Anonymous (Box 66, Folder 3)
      - A-B (Box 66, Folder 4)
      - C (Box 66, Folder 5)
      - D-G [start of reel S60] (Box 66, Folder 6)
      - H-I (Box 66, Folder 7)
      - J-K (Box 66, Folder 8)
      - L-M (Box 66, Folder 9)
      - N-O (Box 67, Folder 1)
      - P (Box 67, Folder 2)
      - R (Box 67, Folder 3)
      - Sa-Sanger, Grant (Box 67, Folder 4)
      - Sanger, Michael-St (Box 67, Folder 5)
      - T-V (Box 67, Folder 6)
      - W-Z (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - Undated correspondence from Margaret Sanger to various correspondents
      - A-Rose (Box 67, Folder 8)
      - Rublee-Z (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - SUBSERIES II. ORGANIZATIONAL RECORDS/CONFERENCE MATERIALS
    - American Birth Control League, 1921-1939
      - General information [start of reel S61] (Box 68, Folder 1)
      - Minutes (Box 68, Folder 2)
      - Publications (Box 68, Folder 3)
      - Form letters (Box 68, Folder 4)
      - Reports (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Birth Control Clinical Research Bureau, 1929-1938
      - General information (Box 68, Folder 6)
      - Minutes (Box 68, Folder 7)
      - Publications (Box 68, Folder 8)
      - Reports, 1929-1931 (Box 68, Folder 9)
      - Report of John Price Jones Co. on fund raising, 1930 (Box 68, Folder 10)
      - Reports, 1931 (Box 68, Folder 11)
      - Reports, 1932 (Box 68, Folder 12)
      - Form letters (Box 68, Folder 13)
    - Joint Committee of the ABCL and BCCRB, 1938-1939
      - Minutes, reports, memorandum, and press releases (Box 68, Folder 14)
    - Birth Control Council of America 1937 [start of reel S62] (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Birth Control Federation of America, 1939-1942
      - General information (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Minutes 1940, 1939-1942 (Box 3)
      - Minutes, 1941-1942 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Minutes 1939 [start of reel S62] (Box 69, Folder 5)
      - Publications (Box 69, Folder 6)
      - Reports (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Form letters, 1939-1942 (Box 8)
    - Birth Control International Information Centre, 1934-1936
      - General information (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Newsletters (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Birth Control Review, New York Women's Publishing Company, 1918-1939
      - General information (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Minutes (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Reports (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Form letters (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Brownsville Clinic, Committee of 100, 1916
      - Advertisement flyer (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - International Committee on Planned Parenthood, 1948-1952
      - General information (Box 70, Folder 1)
      - Organizational memos (Box 70, Folder 2)
      - Reports (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - International Planned Parenthood Federation, 1952-1962
      - General information 1953-1956 [start of reel S63] (Box 70, Folder 4)
      - General information 1957 undated (Box 70, Folder 5)
      - Organizational memos, 1953-1958 (Box 70, Folder 6)
      - Organizational memos, 1959 (Box 70, Folder 7)
      - Minutes, 1953-1957 (Box 70, Folder 8)
      - Minutes, 1958-1959 (Box 70, Folder 9)
      - Minutes, 1960-1962 (Box 70, Folder 10)
      - Publications (Box 70, Folder 11)
      - Reports (Box 70, Folder 12)
      - Form letters (Box 70, Folder 13)
    - Margaret Sanger Research Bureau, 1940-1962
      - General information [start of reel S64] (Box 71, Folder 1)
      - Organizational memos (Box 71, Folder 2)
      - Minutes, 1940-1958 (Box 71, Folder 3)
      - Minutes, 1959 (Box 71, Folder 4)
      - Publications (Box 71, Folder 5)
      - Reports (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - National Committee on Federal Legislation for Birth Control, 1928-1937
      - General information (Box 71, Folder 7)
      - Minutes (Box 71, Folder 8)
      - Publications (Box 71, Folder 9)
      - Newsletters (Box 71, Folder 10)
      - Reports 1929-1934 [start of reel S65] (Box 72, Folder 1)
      - Reports, 1935-1936 (Box 72, Folder 2)
      - Reports, 1937-1938 (Box 72, Folder 3)
      - Form letters (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - New York State Birth Control League, 1916-1918
      - Statement of opening; statement regarding Chicago convention (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Planned Parenthood Federation of America, 1942-1962
      - General information (Box 72, Folder 6)
      - Organizational memos, 1943-1953; 1955-1959 (Box 72, Folder 7)
      - Organizational memos, 1961 (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Minutes 1942-1943, 1942-1962 (Box 9)
      - Minutes, 1944-1952 (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Minutes, 1953-1954 (Box 73, Folder 1)
      - Minutes, 1955-1956 (Box 73, Folder 2)
      - Minutes, 1957-1958 (Box 73, Folder 3)
      - Minutes 1959 [start of reel S66] (Box 73, Folder 4)
      - Minutes, 1960-1962 (Box 73, Folder 5)
      - Publications (Box 73, Folder 9)
      - Reports, 1942-1951 (Box 73, Folder 10)
      - Reports, 1952-1962 (Box 74, Folder 1)
      - Form letters] (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - World Population Emergency Campaign, 1960-1962
      - General information (Box 74, Folder 3)
      - Organizational memos (Box 74, Folder 5)
      - Minutes (Box 74, Folder 4)
      - Publications (Box 74, Folder 6)
      - Reports (Box 74, Folder 7)
      - Form letters (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous organizations, 1919-1957
      - Minutes; miscellaneous (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - International Conferences, 1922-1959
      - 5th International Neo-Malthusian/Birth Control Conference 1922 [start of reel S67] (Box 74, Folder 10)
      - 6th International Neo-Malthusian/Birth Control Conference, 1925 (Box 74, Folder 11)
      - World Population Conference, 1927 (Box 74, Folder 12)
      - 5th International Genetics Congress, 1927 (Box 74, Folder 13)
      - 7th International Birth Control Conference, 1930 (Box 74, Folder 14)
    - Conference on Birth Control in Asia 1933, 1922-1959 (Box 15)
      - International Conference on Population and World Resources, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 16)
      - 3rd International Conference on Planned Parenthood, 1952 [reel S66]
        - General information (Box 74, Folder 17)
        - Programs (Box 74, Folder 18)
        - Form letters (Box 74, Folder 19)
        - Lists (Box 74, Folder 20)
      - 4th International Conference on Planned Parenthood 1953 [reel S67] (Box 74, Folder 21)
      - Western Hemisphere Regional Conference on Population Problems & Family Planning, 1955 (Box 74, Folder 22)
      - 5th International Conference on Planned Parenthood, 1955
        - General information (Box 75, Folder 1)
        - Programs (Box 75, Folder 2)
        - Form letters (Box 75, Folder 3)
      - 6th International Conference on Planned Parenthood (Proposed), 1957 (Box 75, Folder 4)
      - 6th International Conference on Planned Parenthood, 1959 (Box 75, Folder 5)
      - National Conferences, 1921-1930
        - First American Birth Control Conference, 1921 (Box 75, Folder 6)
        - State Birth Control Conferences, 1922-1923 (Box 75, Folder 7)
        - Middle Western States Birth Control Conference, 1923 (Box 75, Folder 8)
        - New York State Birth Control Conference, 1924 (Box 75, Folder 9)
        - Middle Western States Conference on Birth Control, 1929 (Box 75, Folder 10)
        - Eastern Regional States Conference 1929 [start of reel S67] (Box 75, Folder 11)
        - Western States Conference in Birth Control and Population Problems, 1930 (Box 75, Folder 12)
      - National Conferences, 1934-1960
        - American Conference on Birth Control & National Recovery 1934 [start of reel S68] (Box 75, Folder 13)
      - American Conference on Birth Control & National Recovery 1934, 1934-1960 (Box 14)
        - Birth Control Comes of Age Anniversary Dinner, 1935 (Box 76, Folder 1)
        - Conference on Contraceptive Research and Clinical Practice, 1936 (Box 76, Folder 2)
        - Conference on Contraceptive Research and Clinical Practice, 1936 (Box 76, Folder 3)
        - Regional Conference of Western States on Birth Control (Proposed), 1937 (Box 76, Folder 4)
        - Conference on Conservation & Development of Human Resources, 1938 (Box 76, Folder 5)
        - Southern Conference on Tomorrow's Children, 1939 (Box 76, Folder 6)
        - Birth Control Federation of America Conference, 1941 (Box 76, Folder 7)
        - New Look at the Population Crisis Conference, 1960 (Box 76, Folder 8)
        - Miscellaneous conference materials, 1919-1958 (Box 76, Folder 9)
  - SUBSERIES III. LEGAL/GOVERNMENTAL MATERIAL
    - Legal Records, 1917-1936
      - General legal records [start of reel S69] (Box 77, Folder 1)
      - State of New York v. Margaret Sanger et al, 1916-1919 (Box 77, Folder 2)
      - Message Photo-Play v. Bell (Birth Control), 1917 (Box 77, Folder 3)
      - Frederick Blossom/ Margaret Sanger Dispute, 1918 (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Town Hall Raid, 1921 (Box 77, Folder 5)
      - State of New York v. Sideri et al (BCCRB raid), 1929 (Box 77, Folder 6)
      - US v. One Package, 1936 (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Government Records and Legislation, 1917-1936
      - General government records and legislation (Box 77, Folder 8)
      - NY State Legislature, Lindsay Amendment, 1917 (Box 77, Folder 9)
      - NY State Assembly Bill 884 (Rosenman), 1923 (Box 77, Folder 10)
      - NY State Assembly Bill 684 (Gedney), 1927 (Box 77, Folder 11)
      - 71st Congress S.4582 (Gillett), 1930 (Box 77, Folder 12)
      - 72nd Congress H.R.11082 (Hancock), 1932 (Box 77, Folder 13)
      - 72nd Congress S.4436 (Hatfield), 1932 (Box 77, Folder 14)
      - 73rd Congress S.1842 (Hastings) 1933 (Box 77, Folder 15)
      - 73rd Congress H.R.5978 (Pierce), 1933 (Box 77, Folder 16)
      - 74th Congress H.R.5370 (Higgins), 1935 (Box 77, Folder 17)
      - 74th Congress S.600 (Hastings), 1935 (Box 77, Folder 18)
      - 74th Congress H.R. 2000 (Pierce) 1935 (Box 77, Folder 19)
      - 74th Congress H.R. 5600 (Pierce) 1935 [start of reel S69] (Box 77, Folder 20)
      - 74th Congress H.R.11330 (Gassaway), 1936 (Box 77, Folder 21)
      - 74th Congress S.4000 (Copeland), 1936 (Box 77, Folder 22)
  - SUBSERIES IV. WRITINGS
    - Diaries and Journals
      - 1914 [start of reel S70] (Box 78, Folder 1)
      - 1922 (Box 78, Folder 2)
      - Transcription of 1922 diary 2005 (Box 78, Folder 2a)
      - 1924-1927 (Box 78, Folder 3)
      - 1934 (Box 78, Folder 4)
      - 1935 (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - 1936-1939 (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - 1946 (Box 78, Folder 7)
      - 1952 (Box 78, Folder 8)
      - 1954 (Box 78, Folder 9)
      - 1959 (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - Articles and Speeches
      - 1914-1918 (Box 79, Folder 1)
      - 1919 (Box 79, Folder 2)
      - 1920 (Box 79, Folder 3)
      - 1921-1922 (Box 79, Folder 4)
      - 1923 (Box 79, Folder 5)
      - 1924 (Box 79, Folder 6)
      - 1925 [start of reel S71] (Box 79, Folder 7)
      - 1926 (Box 79, Folder 8)
      - 1927-1929 (Box 79, Folder 9)
      - 1930-1931 (Box 79, Folder 10)
      - 1932 (Box 80, Folder 1)
      - 1933 (Box 80, Folder 2)
      - 1934 (Box 80, Folder 3)
      - 1935 (Box 80, Folder 4)
      - 1936 (Box 80, Folder 5)
      - 1937 (Box 80, Folder 6)
      - January-July 1938 (Box 80, Folder 7)
      - October-December 1938 (Box 80, Folder 8)
      - 1939 [start of reel S72] (Box 81, Folder 1)
      - 1940 (Box 81, Folder 2)
      - 1941-1943 (Box 81, Folder 3)
      - 1944 (Box 81, Folder 4)
      - 1945-1949 (Box 81, Folder 5)
      - 1950-1951 (Box 81, Folder 6)
      - 1952 (Box 81, Folder 7)
      - 1953-1954 (Box 82, Folder 1)
      - 1955-1956 (Box 82, Folder 2)
      - 1957-1960 (Box 82, Folder 3)
      - Undated; titled, A-D [start of reel S73] (Box 82, Folder 4)
      - Undated; titled, O-Q (Box 82, Folder 5)
      - Undated; titled, R-Z [found on reel S72] (Box 82, Folder 6)
      - Undated document fragments and notes [found on reel S73] (Box 82, Folder 7)
      - Undated fragments (Box 82, Folder 8)
    - Manuscripts and Books (Box 82)
      - "Superwoman--An Idea for a Movie", 1914-1915 (Box 82, Folder 9)
      - Happiness in Marriage: manuscript, 1926 (Box 82, Folder 10-11)
      - Woman and the New Race, 1920 (Box 82, Folder 12)
      - Motherhood in Bondage, 1928
        - notes, charts, and letters [start of reel S74] (Box 83, Folder 1)
        - draft manuscript (Box 83, Folder 2-3)
        - draft typescript (Box 83, Folder 4-5)
        - draft typescript (Box 83a, Folder 1-3)
      - "The Early History of the Birth Control Movement:" unpublished chapter from My Fight for Birth Control, 1930 (Box 83a, Folder 4)
      - My Fight for Birth Control, 1931
        - typed and handwritten outline and notes [start of reel S75] (Box 83a, Folder 5)
        - handwritten partial draft (Box 83a, Folder 6-7)
        - handwritten partial draft (Box 84, Folder 1)
        - handwritten and typed partial draft (Box 84, Folder 2-3)
        - typed drafts, 1931
          - title page through chapter 5 [start of reel S76] (Box 84, Folder 4)
          - chapters 6-15 (Box 84, Folder 5)
          - chapters 16-26 (Box 84, Folder 6-7)
          - title page through chapter 9 (Box 84, Folder 10)
          - chapters 10-19 (Box 85, Folder 1)
          - chapters 19 (continued) through appendix (Box 85, Folder 2)
          - final draft, title page through chapter 13 (Box 85, Folder 3)
          - final draft, chapter 13 (continued) to appendix B (Box 85, Folder 4)
      - Margaret Sanger: An Autobiography: acknowledgments and pages from draft, 1938 (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Pamphlets
      - Family Limitation 1st ed. (1914), 5th ed. (1916), 6th ed. (1917), 10th ed. (1920), 11th ed. (1921), 12th ed. (1922), 13th ed. to 18th ed. (1923-1927), two revisions without date or number 1914-1927 (Box 85, Folder 6)
      - The Suppressed Obscene Articles, 1914 (Box 85)
      - Dutch Methods of Birth Control, 1915 (Box 85)
      - English Methods of Birth Control, 1915 (Box 85)
      - Magnetation Methods of Birth Control, 1915 (Box 85)
      - Voluntary Motherhood, 1917 (Box 85)
      - Debate on Birth Control between Sanger and Winter Russel, 1920 (Box 85)
      - Appeals from American Mothers, 1921 (Box 85)
      - Woman, Morality, and Birth Control, 1922 (Box 85, Folder 7)
      - For Legalized Birth Control, 1934 (Box 85)
      - Birth Control Through the Ages, 1940 (Box 85)
      - Questions and Answers About Birth Control post-, 1930 (Box 85)
    - Statements and miscellaneous writings, 1921-1934 (Box 85, Folder 8)
    - Statements and miscellaneous writings 1935-1958, undated [start of reel S77] (Box 85, Folder 9)
  - SUBSERIES V. MISCELLANY
    - Awards, Honors, and Tributes
      - General awards, honors, and tributes, 1938-1965 (Box 86, Folder 1)
      - General Luncheons and Dinners in honor of Sanger, 1938-1965 (Box 86, Folder 2)
      - American Women's Association Medal: announcement, 1931 (Box 86, Folder 3)
      - Testimonial Dinner for Sanger: invitations, lists, and correspondence, 1932 (Box 86, Folder 4)
      - Town Hall Club award: press release and proceedings, 1935-1937 (Box 86, Folder 5)
      - Nobel Peace Prize
        - Non-correspondence, 1939-1960 (Box 86, Folder 6)
        - General correspondence, 1939-1960 (Box 86, Folder 7-8)
        - Brush correspondence, 1952-1960 (Box 86, Folder 9)
        - Gamble correspondence, 1952-1960 (Box 86, Folder 10)
        - Schultz correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 86, Folder 11)
        - Watumull correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 86, Folder 12)
        - letters of nomination, 1952-1960 (Box 86, Folder 13)
      - Smith College Honorary LL.D.: correspondence and other material, 1949 (Box 86, Folder 14)
      - Japanese Diet: receptions for Sanger, 1954 (Box 86, Folder 15)
      - Project MS: correspondence and other material, 1957-1959 (Box 87, Folder 1)
      - Our Margaret Sanger (volumes 1 and 2): essays by her friends, relatives, and colleagues 1957-1959 (Box 87, Folder 2)
      - World Tribute to Margaret Sanger: programs, lists, and letters, 1961 (Box 87, Folder 3)
      - Margaret Sanger Testimonial Dinner, Tucson, 1965 (Box 87, Folder 4)
      - Japanese Order of the Precious Crown 1965 [start of reel S78] (Box 87, Folder 5)
      - University of Arizona honorary degree, 1965 (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Planned Parenthood Federation of America International
      - Sponsors Council Tribute, 1966 (Box 88, Folder 1)
      - Plays, poetry, and songs, in honor of Sanger, 1917-1965 (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Luncheons and Dinners
      - Julian Huxley luncheon, 1930 (Box 88, Folder 3)
      - H.G. Wells Dinner, 1931 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Itineraries, tours, and posters, 1916-1960 (Box 88, Folder 5-6)
    - Letters of Introduction (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - Calendars, Datebooks, and Appointment Books
      - 1922 (Box 89, Folder 1)
      - 1922 (Box 89, Folder 2)
      - 1924 (Box 89, Folder 3)
      - 1929 (Box 89, Folder 4)
      - 1930 (Box 89, Folder 5)
      - 1931 (Box 89, Folder 6)
      - 1932 (Box 89, Folder 7)
      - 1932 (Box 89, Folder 8)
      - 1932 (Box 89, Folder 9)
      - 1932 (Box 89, Folder 10)
      - 1933 (Box 89, Folder 11)
      - 1933 (Box 89, Folder 12)
      - 1934 (Box 89, Folder 13)
      - 1934 (Box 89, Folder 14)
      - "Contacts en route to India" 1935 [start of reel S79] (Box 89, Folder 15)
      - 1935 (Box 89, Folder 16)
      - Wall calendar, 1935 (Box 89, Folder 17)
      - 1936 (Box 89, Folder 18)
      - Calendar and diary, 1937 (Box 90, Folder 1)
      - 1938 (Box 90, Folder 2)
      - 1939 (Box 90, Folder 3)
      - 1939 (Box 90, Folder 4)
      - 1939 (Box 90, Folder 5)
      - 1940 (Box 90, Folder 6)
      - 1940 (Box 90, Folder 7)
      - 1941 (Box 90, Folder 8)
      - 1941 (Box 90, Folder 9)
      - Note describing events surrounding illness, July 4-August 6, 1942 [start of reel S80] (Box 91, Folder 1)
      - 1942 (Box 91, Folder 2)
      - 1942 (Box 91, Folder 3)
      - 1942 (Box 91, Folder 4)
      - 1943 (Box 91, Folder 5)
      - 1944 (Box 91, Folder 6)
      - 1945 (Box 91, Folder 7)
      - 1946 (Box 91, Folder 8)
      - 1946 (Box 91, Folder 9)
      - 1947 (Box 91, Folder 10)
      - 1947 (Box 91, Folder 11)
      - 1948 [start of reel S81] (Box 92, Folder 1)
      - 1948 (Box 92, Folder 2)
      - 1948 (Box 92, Folder 3)
      - 1949 (Box 92, Folder 4)
      - 1949 (Box 92, Folder 5)
      - 1949 (Box 92, Folder 6)
      - 1950 (Box 92, Folder 7)
      - 1951 (Box 93, Folder 1)
      - 1952 [start of reel S82] (Box 93, Folder 2)
      - 1953 (Box 93, Folder 3)
      - 1953 (Box 93, Folder 4)
      - 1954 (Box 93, Folder 5)
      - 1955 (Box 94, Folder 1)
      - 1956 (Box 94, Folder 2)
      - 1957 [start of reel S83] (Box 94, Folder 3)
      - 1959 (Box 94, Folder 4)
    - Press Releases and Announcements, 1935-1952 (Box 94, Folder 5)
    - Financial materials, 1950-1960 (Box 94, Folder 6)
    - Contracts (Box 94, Folder 7)
    - Sanger houses (Box 94, Folder 8)
    - Interior design course, 1949 (Box 94, Folder 9)
    - Sanger art exhibits: announcements and lists, 1948-1949 (Box 94)
    - Biographical and autobiographical material 1924-1955, undated (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - Sanger's biographical notes on others 1942-55, undated (Box 95, Folder 2)
    - Notes by Sanger 1930-1958, undated (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - Transcripts of conversations and interviews, 1935-1957 (Box 95, Folder 4)
    - Family material 1921-1922, undated (Box 95, Folder 5)
    - Horoscopes, handwriting analyses, and psychic writings 1922-1943, undated (Box 95, Folder 6)
    - Sanger's death and memorials, 1932-1966 (Box 95, Folder 7)
    - Miscellany 1915-1953, undated (Box 95, Folder 8)